ANKITA RAJ

• ReactJs Developer •ankitaraj655@gmail.com •+91 90366 30696

ABOUT ME

An UI developer with 2.4 years of experience in developing applications (web and desktop) using modern JavaScript library such as ReactJs. I am willing to work for a company where I can help the company grow with my knowledge base, along with personal growth, through continuous process of learning and improvising throughout the course of my career.

EXPERIENCE

Jan 2021- Senior Systems Engineer at Infosys Limited

Present

- Worked as React Developer for a flight based company called Sabre
- Designed reusable user interface components in using ReactJs
- Developed scalable cross-platform desktop application using electron-react-boilerplate
- · Managed application state using react-redux and redux-toolkit
- Used client UI library called spark for development for ReactJs components
- Translated mockup designs into high quality code using ReactJs
- Implemented PowerShell triggering for fetching data from backend
- Implemented electron-json-storage for handling reading and storing the JSON file for frontend rendering
- Wrote jest test cases for all the components, actions and reducers
- Extensively used Git commands for pushing the code into bitbucket
- Participated in continuous enhancement, demo sessions and requirement discussions with client
- Got appreciated for working single handedly for two weeks and increasing the percentage completion of the project

Sep 2020-Dec 2020

Systems Engineer at Infosys Limited

- Worked as React Developer for flight based company called Sabre
- Developed highly scalable cross platform desktop application using electronreact-boilerplate
- Developed responsive reusable components using reactJs
- Used redux for managing application state, and then transformed the application code to use react-redux and redux-toolkit
- Implemented aliased action creators for implementing reading JSON files using electron-json-storage for front end rendering
- Extensively used Git commands for pushing the code into bitbucket
- Participated in business requirement discussions and demo sessions to develop mockup screens

July 2020-Aug 2020

Systems Engineer at Infosys Limited

- Provided enhancements and bug fixes to already developed web application
- Modified HTML and CSS code for responsiveness
- Participated in design enhancement sessions
- Got appreciated for completing the given tasks on time

Aug 2019-

Systems Engineer at Infosys Limited

- May 2020
- Worked as a full-stack developer(MERN) for a US based Banking client
- Developed highly responsive and reusable reactJS components for the web application
- Managed the state of the application using redux
- · Used Ant Design UI library for the development of user interface
- · Provided bug and issue fixes for already developed UI
- Fetched data from backend using Restful API's to display the UI
- Developed new API services using NodeJS and Express, to fetch and manipulate data from database and UI
- Provided bug fixes for already existing services
- Created SQL queries for fetching data from the database
- Extensively used git for pushing the code
- Used JIRA as bug tracking tool to maintains the bugs on a regular basis
- · Participated in business and system requirement discussions

Dec 2018-Apr 2019

Systems Engineer Trainee at Infosys Limited

- Completed Generic Training at Infosys Mysore campus for Various technologies like Pythons, DBMS, OOPS
- Completed Stream training with POC in MERN stack development. Created wanderlust, a travel booking web application using MERN.

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: JavaScript, NodeJs, Express
- UI Frameworks: ReactJS, HTML5, CSS3, Redux, Redux Toolkit, React Hooks
- Package Managers: npm
- Database: MongoDB, MS SQL
- IDE: Visual Studio Code
- SDLC: Agile
- UI Library: Ant Design, Bootstrap
- Other tools: Github, Bitbucket

EDUCATION

2013-2014 •12th Kairali School -75%

2014-2018 • B.E in ISE from MVJCE -72%